<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ModMetaData>
  <name>CodeOptimist's Assorted Alterations</name>
  <author>CodeOptimist</author>
  <url>https://codeoptimism.com/proj/83/</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<size=20>Quality of life modifications.</size>

<color=teal><b>Deny distant material supply jobs.</b></color>
<i>Dry those tears, builders will no longer traverse the entire map for a single component per heater.</i>
Won't supply directly from a resource if hauling it to storage would bring it closer to the given blueprint. (Recommended with <color=grey><b><i>Mehni's</i> Pick Up And Haul</b></color>.)

<color=teal><b>Set default ingredient radius.</b></color>
<i>One less thing to do <b>every, single, time</b>.</i>

<color=teal><b>Shift+scroll cycle area restrictions.</b></color>
Shift + scroll wheel on area restrictions will cycle them for all listed pawns (colonist or animal).
Also recommended: <color=grey><b><i>VouLT's</i> Better Pawn Control</b></color> for policies.

<color=teal><b>Butcher small creatures to conserve freezer space.</b></color>
<i>Leather and meat without worry.</i>
Calculates <= 75 meat yielding creatures.

<color=teal><b>Separate butcher recipes to correctly count meat.</b></color>
<i>Make just what you need; automate your longpig clothing line!</i>
Different recipes to count various combinations of animal, human, and insect.

<color=teal><b>Separate cannibal and insect meals to avoid ingredient mixing.</b></color>
<i>Never again suffer through a single meal contaminating entire stacks.
Feed your favorite brute just what she likes!
Insects to breed and prisoners to feed!</i>

Supports non-vanilla insectoid and humanlike.
Disallowed in starting food restrictions by default.

To preserve balance these extra meal types have:
* Disabled generation (e.g. resource pod drop, map prisoner cell spawn).
* Disabled buying (trade stock generation).
* Disabled scatter on map generation.
<i>Only took 5 hours to study every call to <b>AllDefs</b>...</i>


A heartfelt thanks for addressing these problems initially:
* <color=grey><b><i>Rock5's</i> Butchers Can Count Meat</b></color>
* <color=grey><b><i>Tremeloe's</i> Cook Cannibal Meal (IndividualStack)</b></color>

<size=20>Hello World!</size>

As a programmer who loves this game, I wanted to finally share the improvements and tweaks I've benefited from back to the community, just as so many other modders have improved my experience. I love the small modifications to vanilla that have a huge impact, and am proud to be in the company of others passionate about not necessarily new guns and mechanics and effects, but quality of life on the Rim.
- <color=silver><i>Christopher Galpin (CodeOptimist)</i></color>
]]>
  </description>
</ModMetaData>